Hi, this is CellForge AI, a self-auditing research agent for green lithium-ion battery materials.
Battery researchers face too many papers, too many experimental claims, and too much risk of generating ideas that sound plausible but are not properly grounded.
CellForge AI is not a normal paper-search chatbot. It is a multi-step agent workflow.
It extracts structured claims, benchmarks retrieval, generates hypotheses, audits each hypothesis, traces the process with Arize, and exports an evidence-backed research proposal package.
For this demo, the scope is narrowed to green electrode materials and fabrication methods for lithium-ion batteries.
The agent reads Gemini Document Understanding extraction artifacts, builds a real evidence corpus, and generates five candidate research hypotheses.
The key step is the evidence audit. Each hypothesis is scored for citation coverage, claim grounding, contradiction coverage, and evidence strength.
It is also scored for novelty gap, feasibility, and hallucination risk.
This is what makes CellForge AI different from a regular RAG assistant: it evaluates whether a proposed research direction is supported before recommending it.
In Arize AX, every major decision becomes inspectable.
The trace view shows evidence loading, retrieval, hypothesis generation, evaluator spans, and self-introspection.
The self-introspection stage selects hypothesis H003 because it has stronger grounding and lower hallucination risk than the alternatives.
The selected hypothesis is circular natural-graphite anodes with bio-based conductive surface repair.
It combines non-thermal plasma purification for natural or recycled graphite with a bio-derived carbon coating that may repair surface defects and stabilize the solid electrolyte interphase.
CellForge also keeps risk visible. For example, PHBV binder evidence shows strong cycling performance, but it uses chloroform and has lower adhesion than PVDF.
Instead of ignoring this, the agent treats it as contradiction and risk-control evidence.
After the audit, CellForge applies a human validation gate.
In this demo, four critical claims are validated from Gemini Document Understanding artifacts and internal consistency checks.
Finally, Gemini Pro preview generates the research brief, and the repository exports a manuscript draft plus a molecular interface schematic.
The output is not an automatically publishable final paper. It is an evidence-backed research proposal package that a human researcher can validate, edit, and develop.
CellForge AI starts with green battery materials because the future of clean energy, electric vehicles, and sustainable industry depends on better materials and cleaner battery manufacturing.