Hi, this is CellForge AI, a self-auditing research agent for green lithium-ion battery materials.
Battery researchers face too many papers, too many experimental claims, and too much risk of generating a plausible but ungrounded research idea.
CellForge AI is not a normal paper-search chatbot. It is a multi-step agent workflow that extracts claims, benchmarks retrieval, generates hypotheses, audits them, and exports a proposal package.
For this demo, the scope is green electrode materials and fabrication methods for lithium-ion batteries. The agent uses Gemini extraction artifacts to build a real evidence corpus.
The key step is the evidence audit. Each hypothesis is scored for citation coverage, claim grounding, contradiction coverage, evidence strength, novelty, feasibility, and hallucination risk.
In Arize AX, every major agent decision is inspectable: retrieval, hypothesis generation, evaluator spans, and self-introspection.
The self-introspection stage selects H003: circular natural-graphite anodes with bio-based conductive surface repair.
The agent also keeps risk visible. PHBV binder evidence has strong cycling performance, but it uses chloroform and has lower adhesion than PVDF.
After the audit, CellForge applies a human validation gate. In this demo, four critical claims are validated from Gemini extraction artifacts and consistency checks.
Finally, Gemini Pro preview generates the research brief, and the repository exports a manuscript draft plus a molecular interface schematic.
This is not an automatically publishable final paper. It is an evidence-backed research proposal package for a human researcher to validate and develop.